Please invite the Yan Dong envoy to the court
请燕东使者上殿
Greetings, Your Majesty
参见陛下
Envoy, please rise
使者请起
Your Majesty
陛下
For decades
数十年以来
Our Yan Dong court
我们燕东朝堂
Has still held Xuan Kingdom's credentials
依旧持宣国符节
And considers itself a vassal state of Xuan
自认为是宣朝封国
Now my father has sent me
今父皇遣我来
Hoping even more
更是希望
To be able to
能与陛下
Restore our former friendship with Your Majesty
重归旧好
We are willing to offer ten thousand fine horses
我们愿以万匹良驹
To marry a princess
迎娶一位公主
As queen
作为王后
From then on
自此
With Great Xuan
和大宣
We will work together in harmony
和衷共济
Sharing the same spirit
同气
And connected branches
连枝
This proposal
这个提议
I will consider it
朕会考虑的
The Yan Dong envoy has come from afar
燕东使节远道而来
After a long journey
舟车劳顿
Please
还请
Return early to rest
先早些回去休息吧
Thank you, Your Majesty
谢陛下
Excellent
太好了
Yan Dong
燕东
Is willing to help us attack Wuzhao
这是肯为咱们攻伐邬伖出力了
But they want to marry a princess
可他们要娶公主
Isn't there only Princess Xunyang in the palace?
宫中不就只有一位浔阳公主
Right
对
Just marry Princess Xunyang off to them
就把浔阳公主嫁过去
Alright
好了
Let's discuss the next matter
先议下一件事
Your Majesty
陛下
Lady Liu is still kneeling outside
刘昭仪还在外头跪着呢
We can't persuade her to leave
劝不走啊
Your Majesty
陛下
When you were in Yiyang, you promised Grandfather
你在弋阳的时候答应过爷爷
To protect me
要护臣妾
In peace and happiness for life
一世平安喜乐
I want nothing
臣妾什么都不要
I beg you, don't let Yu'er leave
求你别让钰儿走
Rise first
先起来
Your Majesty
陛下
Don't let Yu'er leave
别让钰儿离开
I beg you
臣妾求您了
Listen to me
听朕的话
Return to the palace first
先回宫
Father
父皇
Yan Dong has also been harassed by Wuzhao for years
燕东也常年受邬伖袭扰
Your son believes
儿臣以为
If the two states can form a marriage alliance
两国若能结秦晋之好
To watch over each other and together drive out Wuzhao
守望相助 共逐邬伖
Would be the best strategy
乃是上上之法
Sikong Sheng
司空盛
You're a coward
你就是个窝囊废
That's your sister
那是你妹妹
How can you let her marry to a place like Yan Dong
你怎么可以让她嫁到燕东那种
A remote and poor place to suffer
偏远贫贱之地受苦
With Yan Dong's assistance
有燕东助力
How many fewer of our people would die
我国可以少死多少人
To let my sister marry far away
让妹妹远嫁
How could I not be heartbroken
我怎可能不为之心痛
But as members of the royal family
可既为宗室
Why not bear the responsibility for the people
为何不背负起百姓的责任
Do you think the people kneel to you
你以为百姓凭什么跪你
Kneel to me
跪我
Kneel to Princess Xunyang
跪她浔阳公主
Father
父皇
If the state and realm
若江山社稷
Must rely on Yu'er, a mere woman
要靠阿钰一介女流
To bring stability and revival
来安稳复兴
Then what use are all the men in court
那要这满朝男儿做甚
Father
父皇
Your son is willing to be the vanguard
儿臣愿为先锋
On the day of the northern expedition
来日北征
To defeat Wuzhao
杀破邬伖
Father's lifelong efforts
父皇半生心血
Have all been for reviving Great Xuan
皆为复兴大宣
You are the father of all under heaven
是这天下的君父
Should not be limited to one family
不当囿于一家一姓
By personal affections
儿女情长
All rise
都起来吧
I
朕
Will make my own decision
自有决断
Your Majesty
陛下
The Ministry of Rites just sent someone to ask again
礼部刚刚又差人来问
Only a few days left before the envoy returns
离使者返程就剩几天
We must have an answer
总得有个答复啊
Before
之前
I asked you to sound her out
我让你旁敲侧击
To ask Xunyang's thoughts
问问浔阳的想法
The princess cares for Your Majesty
公主心疼陛下
This servant sees
奴才瞧着
She is willing to go
是肯去的
She said nothing else
没说别的
This
这
To leave home thousands of miles away
去家万里
Sorrow is inevitable
伤心难免
But Princess Xunyang is filial
但浔阳公主孝顺
She would never go against Your Majesty's wishes
断不会忤逆陛下意思的